Association for Research and Enlightenment Collection
The Edgar Cayce Foundation
- Publications, 1931 2015
  - Box 5
    - A.R.E. News, 1970; Folder 5:11; Landers, Olive; Cayce, Hugh Lynn; Irion, J. Everett; Trop, June; Morris, William F.; January, 1970 -Winter Conferences at ARE, Virginia Beach -An Unusual Gift (James Churchward drawings) -Dictionary of Definitions -Attention: Prospective ARE Writers -Study Group News -Membership Message -Council News -ARE Library News -Feedline -Visitor from Denmark (Eric Jungfalk) -Naming the Baby (ARE Children's Magazine) -Our Ubiquitous Lecturer (Elsie Sechrist) February, 1970 -A Feast of Tempting Treats Offered in the Spring Conferences at Virginia Beach Headquarters -Texas Statewide Conference -The Oxpetals -Important Course - UCLA -Study Group News -Membership Message -Council News -ARE Library News -An Eminent Visitor (Raynor Johnson) -Campsite Activities - 1970 -A Welcome Adjunct (Marguerite Haugen) -Feedline -First Braille Product ARE 1970 Calendar of Events: March, April, May, June March, 1970 -Asilomar ARE Family Workshop -The Crystal Skull (HLC visit to Frank Dorland) -Basic Concepts - Search for God Week -What About Atlantis? -Leading Spring Lecturers at Headquarters -European Psychical Research Tour -Study Group News -Council News -Membership Message -ARE Library News -Announcements and Appeals -Corrections -Feedline April, 1970 -Dr. Cayce to Head ARE Youth Program (Charles Thomas Cayce) -Dr. Raynor C. Johnson's Lectures -Visitor from Afar (Miriam Price) -Special Program: ESP and Psychic Phenomena -Council News -Study Group News -Membership Message -ARE Library News -Visitor from the Past (Booker T. Avery) -New York ARE Spring Conference -First New Jersey Tri-Metro New Age Seminar May 8, 1970 -invitation to attend Raynor Johnson lectures May, 1970 -Edgar Cayce Memorial Library Building Fund -A Unique Contribution (dowsing by Louis J. Matacia) -Opportunity for Service (registered nurse for the Edgar Cayce Therapy Department) -Group Stimulation Conferences -Television Appearances (HLC) -Trip with Highlights (Wilfred and Elsie Sechrist) -Study Group News -Membership Message -Camp Promise -visit by Rev. Marjorie H. Russell -lecture by Edith Wallace, M.D, Ph.D. -ARE Library News -Council News -Atlantis Again! -The Marshalls -retraction (New Jersey Tri-Metro New Age Seminar in no way connected to ARE) June, 1970 -Edgar Cayce Memorial Library Building Fund -Art Conference, Youth Conference -Meeting a Need (Heritage Store) -Substantial Appreciation (donation in honor of Dr. Harold J. Reilly's 75th birthday) -Feedline -Study Group News -Nuggets from Council Newsletters -To Be Seen at ARE Camp Virginia 1970 -ARE Library News -High School Free-Form Curriculum Supplemented by ARE Lecturers -Prayer Has Power -A Tribute (Los Angeles and Orange County California Councils) June, 1970 Department Profile: Department of Membership Services; ARE Clinic -Edgar Cayce Memorial Building Fund -New ARE Creative Project and Service (June Trop, Braille translation) -Are You Contest-Minded? (ARE elevator speech) -Feedline -New Youth Lounge -historical marker in Hopkinsville, Kentucky -Questions Answered -Snapshots Here and There (HLC, Anne Schreiner, Sean Cayce Gaston, Raynor Johnson, Mrs. Johnson, Sally Cayce, Linda Quest, William Lord, Fonchen Lord) -Study Group News -Membership Message -Gleanings from Council Newsletters -Department Profile: The Accounting Department -ARE Library News -Blimp-Like Craft May Move the Commuters of Tomorrow -An Open Letter to Mr. and Mrs. F. Soloman -1970 Conference Program -ARE Camp Construction August, 1970 -Psychic Discoveries Behind the Iron Curtain (Lynn Schroeder and Sheila Ostrander) -Musical Note -Feedline -Youth Conference at Camp -Summertime Doings -Briefly Told By Mrs. Johnson -Profiles Continued: Headquarters Staff -Study Group News -Wanted - Channels! -Council News -What Some Former Members Write Us -Important! Circulating Files Users -Read Round the World (Many Mansions) -Dreams That Prompted Action -ARE Library News -Two New Books by Krajenke -New Plans for Atlantic University -For Refreshment and Renewal (weekend retreats) July 1970 -1969 Statement of Operations by J. Everett Irion September, 1970 -Edgar Cayce Memorial Library Building Fund -A Pathfinder by Choice (Dr. Shafica Karagulla) -George and Magdalen Houdeshel purchase Ruben Miller's interest in the Marshalls -Feedline -Fresh News About Our Braille Program (June Trop) -About the Cayce Movie -Herbs to Our Aid -An Outstanding Event (Fall Seminar, Greater Kansas City) -New Products List -Coronet Series on Cayce -New Regional Representative (Mary Virginia Cobb) -Study Group News -Guardian of the Garden (Edward Pankowski) -ARE Library News -Unusual Acquisition (Thomas Jay Hudson book) -Important Figure at the Marshalls (Simpson Machen) -Second Chiropractic Seminar at ARE to Feature Dr. Bernard Jensen -Appeal to Photographers October, 1970 -A Call That Succeeded (volunteer workers) -Edgar Cayce Memorial Library Building Fund -New Discoveries (related to The Great Migration booklet) -Feedline -A Week of Awakening (William F. Morris, on Organic Living conference) -Where Youth Met Youth (ARE Youth Lounge, Margaret Jett) -A Promising Project (Project Aquarius lecture series for colleges) -Two-Man Show (ARE Art Show; Mary Ellen Carter, Victor Zaikine) -ARE Library News -Elsie's Book Still Traveling -Therapy Department Announcement -New Tapes Available -Magnolia Tree at Headquarters dedicated to Study Group No. 1 November, 1970 -Edgar Cayce Memorial Library Building Fund -Youth Activities -This Could be Atlantis! -- If Not, What? -Jottings from Among the Conferees at Leadership Training -What is Science? -Study Group News -Membership Message -Dreams Have Their Day as Well as Night -Education and Group Work Departments -A Canadian Weekender -ARE Library News -Surprise Encounter (S.C. Batra) -New Regional Representative (Edward M. Sloan, Jr.) -Call for Volunteers (ARE Journal indexing) December, 1970 -Edgar Cayce Memorial Library Building Fund -Contest Winners -Feedline -Fourth Annual ARE Medical Symposium -A Promising Partnership (Academy of Parapsychology and Medicine) -Dictionary of Definitions from the Readings -Study Group News -Membership Message -ARE Youth Program -Youth Conference Planning in Texas -Press Profile -Activities at the Marshalls -Successful Seminar (Chiropractic Research Seminar) -ARE Library News -New Features for the Children -A Step Forward in Psychic Research -A Rare Treat (Sechrist lectures on Russia and the Holy Trail) Cayce family Christmas card Christ Through the Ages: Sonnets by Lucia Clark Markham, Correlated with Selections from the Edgar Cayce Readings order form
    - A.R.E. News, 1971; Folder 5:12; Landers, Olive; Boykin, Louis; McGarey, William; Adams, Frank; Trop, June; LaPrelle, John; Baker, Penny; January, 1971 -100th Life Member Amazed (Morgan Delar Rayburn) -Dictionary of Definitions from the Readings -Feedline -An Experience in Service and Cooperation (Walnut Acres Organic Farm) -ESP Workshop -ARE Press Profile -Study Group News -Membership Message -Coming ARE Conferences and Workshops Across the Country -ARE Library News -A Good Turn (Harry Calkin) -Health Note brochure, ARE Publications based on the Edgar Cayce Readings February, 1971 -Edgar Cayce Memorial Library Building Fund -Affirmations in Song (songbook based on A Search for God) -Rescuers Rewarded (John A. Nichols rescued from water by Robert Newman and Edward Pankowski) -Feedline -Gleanings -Holiday Conference Snapshots -Study Group News -Membership Message -Golden Age Week -Edgar Cayce and Group Dynamics -Youth Activities -ARE Library News -School for Children -Recital (Mr. and Mrs. James Morrison) -Reference File Indexes Available -Council Jottings March, 1971 -Edgar Cayce Memorial Library Building Fund -A Reader With A Heart (anonymous donation to send books to prisons at Veteran's Hospitals) -Committee at Work (Edgar Cayce Memorial Library Committee: James Embleton, Edgar Evans Cayce, Jane Killen, Robert Adriance, J. Everett Irion) -At Your Service (Edward and Jo Cavanagh) -Feedline -Col. Frank Adams on Tour for ARE -lectures by Mary Ann Woodward and Lucille Kahn -Profile of Readings Research Department -Youth Workshop -Study Group News -Membership Message -A Conference Designed for Ministers -Texas Statewide Conference -An Irresistible Appeal (State Correctional Institution at Pittsburgh) -Youth Activities -A Letter from the New ARE Camp Director (Louis Boykin) -Especially for Students -ARE Library News -Thank You Letter, Membership Services -ARE Treasure Trove order form April, 1971 -Edgar Cayce Memorial Library Building Fund -Visitor from the Past (B.J. Macauley, M.D.) -Successful Medical Symposium -Feedline -Everybody a Gardener -Cooperation in Action -Sent us by William McGarey, M.D. of the ARE Clinic, Phoenix, Arizona -Study Group News -What Stones and Metals May Do for Us -Youth Activities -Study at ARE for College Credit -ARE Library News -A Positive Approach to Negative ESP -Stranger in the Earth (reprinted in paperback) -Let There Be Light (booklet printed during WWII) May, 1971 -Edgar Cayce Memorial Library Building Fund -Coming Chiropractic Seminar (Herbert Goloff, D.C., Robert George Brewer, M.D.) -Edgar Cayce's Earth Changes Agree with Modern Findings (Charles S. Hapgood) -Braille Performer (Sibyl Schneller) -Feedline -The Happiest Man (Harold Fenwick) -Hugh Lynn Cayce Says -A Testimony -Youth Activities -Study Group News -Membership Message -Organic Gardening Produces Pure Foods -ARE Library News -Nutrition a Spiritual Matter -Watch for It (Elsie Sechrist on the Mike Douglas Show) June, 1971 -Edgar Cayce Memorial Library Building Fund -Letter from England (Col. Frank Adams) -Braille Brevities (June Trop) -Feedline -News from the ARE Clinic -A Member's Psychic Experience -A Bright Spot (Joy Smiley) -ARE Good Samaritans (Cynthia and Dr. Lindsay Jacob) -Planting the Promise: A Young Man's Experience (John LaPrelle) -Study Group News -Membership Message -Nell Clairmonte on Tour -Council Correspondence -Youth Activities -ARE Library News July, 1971 -Edgar Cayce Memorial Library Building Fund -More About the New Library Building -New Addition to Marshalls Ownership (Mary and Gene Mueller) -New at Headquarters (Richard Holcombe) -Attention: Ham Radio Operators (Lester Babcoke) -In New York (Jack Raymond Rice III new executive director of ARE New York Center) -Feedline -A Penal Institution First (Lowell Florida first official prison ARE Study Group) -Some Psychic Experiences and Dreams -aerial photographs of Headquarters campus -Youth Activities -Study Group News -Membership Message -Letters from Members -ARE Library News -Gleanings August, 1971 -Edgar Cayce Memorial Library Building Fund -Important Innovations Indicate New Horizons -ARE Forty Years Old -Change Is For Welcoming! -Feedline -Braille Brevities -Psychic Experiences at Sea -Youth Activities -Membership Message -New Psychical Group (Psychical Research Association of Wisconsin) -Study Group News -New Information Center, Virginia Beach Headquarters Entrance Hall -New Board of Trustees -A.R.E. Library News -One Way to Get There! (joint member trips to conferences) -News Notes September, 1971 -Edgar Cayce Memorial Library Building Fund Report -Eminent Visitor Coming (Professor Charles H. Hapgood) -Hail and Farewell! (retirement of Commander Harold G. Allen, Director of ARE Press and Publications) -Chiropractic Seminar -Feedline -Will They Win the Bequest? (James Kidd) -Psychic Experiences -Study Group News -Council Correspondence -ARE Workshop in Europe -Domesticity Defied -North Texas Fall Conference -Youth Activities -Humor from the Readings -Membership Message -Modern Medicine and the Spirit lecture by William McGarey -ARE Library News -ARE Clinic Idea Appreciated -Tell It As You Find It October, 1971 -Edgar Cayce Memorial Library Building Fund -Official Trip to Russia -Products and Promises of Tombs and Sphinx -Feedline -Symposium on Healing -Psychic Experiences -Membership Message -Youth Activities -Humor from the Readings -Study Group News -ARE Library News -Write Your Experience Please November, 1971 -Edgar Cayce Memorial Library Building Fund -An Important Selection (committee to find Executive Director for ARE) -ARE Goes to Russia (Penny Baker) -Feedline -New Membership Participation in ARE -Membership Message -Humor from the Readings -Study Group News -Our Conferees - What Are They Like? -Youth Activities -ARE Library News -Introducing Kora (new Press equipment) -Summer Issue of Treasure Trove Now Available) -A First Shovelful! (new Edgar Cayce Memorial Library Building) December, 1971 -Edgar Cayce Memorial Library Building Fund -ARE Medical Symposium -Phoenix ARE Clinic's Physical Therapy Unit -Feedline -ARE Tourists in Russia -Membership Message -Youth Activities -Study Group News -Psychic Experience -Humor from the Readings -ARE Library News -She Came Back Later(Virginia Summers) -Telling the Girls (HLC at Girls Service Organization Eastern Seaboard Weekend Conference) -Our Travelers Write
    - A.R.E. News, 1972; Folder 5:13; Landers, Olive; Trop, June; Baker, Penny; Krajenke, Robert; January, 1972 -Edgar Cayce Memorial Library Building Fund -Achievement Achieved! (Gladys Davis Turner and EC Reading Indexing Project) -Feedline -A.R.E. Goes to Russia -Membership Message -More Views of A.R.E. Party in Russia -Study Group News -Youth Activities -ARE Library News -Humor from the Readings -Braille Brevities (June Trop) February, 1972 -Edgar Cayce Memorial Library Building Fund -James R. Embleton Appointed as Executive Director -Library Architectural Firm Selected -June Congress Week Grows in Depth -A Time for Rebirth: Easter Meditation Retreat -1972 Calendar for the Field -Feedline -Humor from the Readings -Interview with Hugh Lynn Cayce -Russian Tour: Final Installment (Penny Baker) -A Report on Consciousness -Highlights from the Holiday Youth Conference (Robert W. Krajenke) -Views of the Conference -Study Group News -ARE Library News -Can You Make Anything of This Dream? (Theora Hamblett) -In Memoriam (Fernande Fern Turgeon) -Jottings from Lectures at ARE Headquarters, Virginia Beach -Inner and Outer (Herb Puryear) March, 1972 -Edgar Cayce Memorial Library Building Fund -Board of Advisors -Meditation a Spiritual Discipline -Harmon Bro, June Bro, Walter Starcke at the Easter Meditation Retreat -Feedline -Two Personal Experiences -Study Group News -Religious Experience Investigated -Psychic Experiences -Youth Activities -Report on Consciousness -Membership Message -Welcome Awaits You (Marshalls Hotel) -ARE Campers and Conferees -Humor from the Readings -ARE Library News -Our Vigilant Correspondents -update on Lydia Schrader Gray -New ARE Telephone Listing for Chicago -A Winning Team (Nell Clairmonte and Gladys Davis Turner tour) -Elsie and Bill Sechrist tour April, 1972 -Library Building Fund -Your Chance to Help Govern -list of regional representatives to attend Congress -A Great Education Endeavor (The Association of Learning college courses under charter of Atlantic University) -Feedline -This Year's Medical Symposium the Best Yet -Study Group News -Lecture and Conference Notes -Successful Western Conferences -Membership Message -Youth Activities -ARE Library News -Children's Search for God -Bargain Flights Possible to ARE Members -Try This One (new Circulating File, Cycle of the Soul) -Popular Spot (guests at the Marshalls) -Psychic Experiences May, 1972 -"Who Is Man?" TV Show Available for Your Town (Hugh Lynn Cayce, Herbert Puryear, Boyd Harrier with Hampton Roads Educational Television) -A 1935 Reading Sets the Theme for 1972 Congress -ARE Membership Around-the-World Study Tour -Association of Learning Summer Sessions Garner Quick Response -Feedline -Study Group News -Search for God Groups in Prison -Membership Message -The Busy Baraffs (Carol and Jim Baraff) -A Thief with Manners (Phyllis Mainz) -New Circulating File (Jesus - The Pattern and You) -Conference and Lecture Notes -Youth Activities -ARE Library News -Library Building Fund -Music As The Bridge: A Talk with Author of our Newest Booklet (Shirley Rabb Winston) -Eula Allen's Trilogy in New Format June, 1972 -Conference on Healing in the New Age -Our International Representatives: A Glowing "First" (Bill and Elsie Sechrist) -Feedline -Cooperating Nurses Unit -Thelma Barrett new full-time Head Receptionist at Headquarters -Study Group News -Knowledge: The Greatest Gift -Letters -Humor from the Readings -Membership Message (ARE financial report; list of elected delegates to the Congress Week in June) -Youth Activities -ARE Library News -Library Building Fund -Young and Old Must Meet in the Middle - No Gap! (Walter Starcke) -New Book: Edgar Cayce on Healing July, 1972 -Atlantic University Finds First Facilities -Hindu Holy Man Makes a Surprise Visit to the ARE (Faquir Dayal and I.C. Sharma) -Feedline -Membership Message -Letters -Study Group News -Time, Space, Patience - A Puzzling Trio -Correction (Marshalls Price List) -Congress Week: A Successful Dialogue Sets the Tone for ARE's Future -Miss Gladys Revisits Selma -A New Feature: Beauty Spot -Youth Activities -ARE Library News -About Our Busy Braillists -Book News (My Years with Edgar Cayce) -An Unusual Feature (Frances Willard reincarnation at the Marshalls Hotel) August, 1972 -Edgar Cayce Would Have Been Proud (40th Annual June Congress) -Recommendations at Congress of Membership Committee) -Feedline -Membership Message -Four New Trustees Elected to Board (Beverly Simmons, Rudolph Johnson, Robert Jeffries, Eugene Mueller) -Congress Snapshots -Study Group News -Coming Events -Recommendations at Congress of Study Group Committee -Recommendations at Congress of Education Committee -Help Needed: ARE Clinic Outpatient Residence, Phoenix, Arizona -Dr. McGarey Addresses 1,500 Physicians on Acupuncture -Beauty Spot -ARE Library News -Osteopathic Magazine Features Edgar Cayce -Tape Library Moved to Virginia Beach -An Explanation (advertisements in Edgar Cayce On... paperback series) -Using Available Readings Research Material -Results of Congress Poll on Publications September, 1972 -A Day in the Life of Atlantic University -A Walking Miracle (excerpt from The Sun, Virginia Beach) -Feedline -Letter (Mrs. Walter Clark) -Youth Conferences at Virginia Beach Headquarters -Study Group News -An Opportunity to Help: Prison Inmates Recording for Braille Library Need More Equipment -Membership Message -Beauty Spot -ARE Library News -Films Available On Loan (Gladys Davis Turner and Hugh Lynn Cayce on Topic; Harold Reilly and Hugh Lynn Cayce on Topic; Venture Inward; Bill and Elsie Sechrist and Hugh Lynn Cayce on Topic; Davis Kahn Interview by Tomlin Films; LA Study Group) -Slides Available (Mining the Wealth; The Story of the Revelation; Kundaline) -Tape Library: New Address -From the Philippines (Mrs. W.D. Vinson) -Ham Radio Operators! (Paul Hooper) -Psychic Experience October, 1972 -Letter from a Grateful Member (John. L. Styer, Jr.) -Research Center for Advancement in Total Healing (Robert G. Brewer, M.D.) -Questionnaire Response -Adult Workshop at Asilomar -Feedline -Membership Message -Atlantic University at Rural Retreat -A Word to Parents from the Edgar Cayce Readings -Study Group News -About the ARE Braille Library -A Visitor from Belgium (Tina Fransen) -You Can Control Your Sleep (Velma P. Gordon) -An Apology (Warner Paperback Library) -Beauty Spot -ARE Library News -Library Building Fund Report -Gina Cerminara on General Semantics -Jeffrey Furst;s New Book (Edgar Cayce's Story of Attitudes and Emotions) November, 1972 -Atlantic University Announces Winter Session: Expands Program for Summer '73 -ARE Clinic Entering Fourth Year: Dates Announces for Sixth Medical Symposium -Feedline -Parent's Column -Study Group News -Hugh Lynn Cayce Interviewed in Psychic Magazine -Membership Message -Study Groups in Prison Are Growing -The Blind and Hatha Yoga -Report from the President -Advisory Board Election -A Motion Picture on Edgar Cayce's Life and Work -Heritage Store Booklet -Policies With Regard to Psychical Research -Introductory Film Report -Looking to the Future: ARE Purchases Video Equipment -Beauty Spot -Healing Week Attracts Capacity Attendance -A Report on the Fourth Annual Chiropractic Seminar -ARE Library News -Now in Paperback -A Story of Edgar Cayce for Children -Dreams of Businessmen Requested -A Dream Lesson December, 1972 -Final Design for New Library Approved -Feedline -Membership Message -Study Group News -Worth Wends Westward (Worth Kidd) -Another First As Alaska Interest Grows -ARE Medical Policy - An Explanation -The Oldest Member? (Robert J. Simon) -Parent's Column -A Message to All Her Friends from Lydia J. Schrader Gray -Glad Helpers Prayer Group Spans the World -Special Sale on Dr. Reilly's Book -Beauty Spot -Report on First ARE Europe and Middle East Student Tour -ARE Library News -Helpful Hints for Ordering Tapes -Now in Paperback -An Illustrated Children's Book in Braille -Christmas Message 1972 -Cayce family Christmas card
  - Box 6